govteen.com 2001-04-13

# Welcome to Gov!

**GOV's Privacy Policy**  
---  
**GOV is committed to safeguarding your privacy online.

Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically.

**  

**This policy will let you know:**  
  
**1\. What personally identifiable information is collected from you  
2\. What cookies are and how they are used.  
3\. How your information is used.  
4\. Who is collecting your information.  
5\. With whom your information may be shared.  
6\. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information.  
7\. How you can access, update or delete your information.;  
8\. How GOV treats your personal financial and health-related information..  
9\. The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information.  
10\. How GOV protects children's privacy. and  
11\. What else you should know about your online privacy.**  

**NOTICE:[Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission.**  

**What personally identifiable information does GOV collect from me?**  
  
GOV collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites.

Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, GOV asks for your: (Required information is shown in larger print) 

  * **User Name**
  * **Password**
  * **Email Address**
  * **City, State, Country**
  * **Occupation**
  * **Homepage URL**
  * **Interests**
  * **Gender**
  * **ICQ Number**
  * **AIM Screen Name**
  * **Yahoo ID**
  * **Signature**

Only your user name, password and email address are required for you to register and use the Service. Storage of the remaining information in your profile is optional and is provided for those members who find this feature useful or who want to make this personally identified information viewable to the public. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to GOV - you are given a GOV member name or nick name that you select and are able to take full advantage of GOV's many offerings. 

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by GOV and/or our many partners; when you make a purchase using GOVTradingPost or GOVBizCenter; when you post a GOV classified ad; when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services.

GOV may also ask for other information about you or related to any question you may ask GOV or a GOV volunteer by email or on our message boards or chat rooms to clarify your question or to request information needed to answer your question or to verify registration information. If you contact GOV we may keep a record of that correspondence. GOV also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever GOV collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.   

**What are cookies and how does GOV use them?**  

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, GOV uses [**cookies**](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/cookie.htm) to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All sites on GOV where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies. 

**Generally, we use cookies to:**

(1) Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services.

(2) Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of GOV's network of web sites you have visited, and users visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on GOV a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites. 

Advertising networks that serve ads on GOV may also use their own cookies. 

GOV also collects [**IP addresses**](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/TERM/I/IP_address.html) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, GOVPostOffice includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers.  

**How does GOV use my information?**  

GOV's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our network of sites. This includes personalization services, interactive communications, online shopping and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, GOV is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. You will only receive special notices via email from GOV if you have indicated in your member profile preferences that you would like to receive GOV notices and newsletters. You can change your account preferences at any time. 

GOV does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. GOV may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners. GOV does not use your account information to conduct demographic studies or for marketing purposes.   

**Who is collecting information?**  

When you are on a GOV site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with GOV alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. For example, some GOV services, like GOVTradingPost, are offered in conjunction with a partner company. In order to provide this co-branded service to you, it is necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner company. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than GOV, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Promotions that run on GOV may be sponsored by companies other than GOV or may be cosponsored by GOV and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared. 

Please be aware that GOV Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites linked to GOV are not covered by this privacy policy and GOV has no control over the policies of others.   

**With whom does GOV share my information?**  

As a general rule, GOV will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. 

**Business Partners & Sponsors**: GOV may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Service or Use Agreements, and sweepstakes and promotions rules. Some or all data collected during a GOV promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. 

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give GOV permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer. 

**GOV Stores & Shopping**: If you make a purchase from a store hosted by GOVTradingPost or GOVBizCenter, or a merchant in GOVTradingPost or GOVBizCenter, the information obtained during your visit to those stores, and the information you give such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to the merchants. This is to enable transactions to take place. 

Merchants listed in GOVTradingPost or GOVBizCenter have separate privacy and data collection practices. GOV has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their **Privacy Policy** link. 

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, GOV will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them . 

**Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate**: Under confidentiality agreements, GOV may match user information with third party data. Also, GOV discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to current and prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

**Other:** GOV may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating GOV's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) GOV's rights or property, other GOV users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. GOV may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.   

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**  

GOV may, from time to time, send you email and newsletter regarding our products and services. Only GOV will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily edit your GOV member profile to no longer receive such offers and mailings. You will need your GOV ID and Password in order to access your GOV member profile 

On some types of GOV promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related email, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements. 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those GOV services that require registration in order to participate. You can still use GOV chat and message boards many other GOV site features even if you do not accept cookies. 

GOV does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.   

**What is GOV's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?**  

You may update, correct or delete your GOV member profile at any time by using your GOV member name and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click here to request a new password.

Your GOV account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so will result in not being able to access any members-only area of the GOV network, including your GOVPostOffice account (if you have one). Click here to delete your account at any time. Residual information will remain within our archive records.   

**How does GOV protect my personal financial and health-related information?**  

Keeping your personal financial and health-related information private is vitally important to us. As with all information, GOV will never rent or sell your personal financial or health-related information.

Knowing that you use certain services or features may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial product or service usage on GOV are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user. 

Please note that there are several places on the GOV network of Web sites where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes. Any time we ask for a credit card number we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption.   

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**  

Your GOV Account Information are password-protected so that only GOV, a limited under of volunteer system administrators and you have access to this personal information. You may edit or delete your GOV Account Information by using your GOV ID and password.

GOV's GOVKid, GOVTeen, GOVcollege, GOVParent, and GOVGrandparent network of sites are managed and operated by GOV and volunteers. A few volunteers may have access to administrative areas of our web sites. These volunteers are required to follow the same privacy policies set by GOV by this disclosure of our Privacy Policy. The Volunteers having this access may be from age 7 to 12 for GOVKid and age 13 and over for other GOV web sites and have been instructed not to give out personal information about any member without GOV's authorization.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. GOV will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your GOV account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

As an international company GOV has international sites and users all over the world. When you give GOV personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever GOV handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, GOV takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, GOV cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.  

**What about children's privacy?**  

Naturally, the safety of children is very important to us. GOV recommends that parents and kids try GOVKid, a web guide designed especially for users between the ages of 7 and 12. Sites listed on GOVKid have all been selected by GOV. This selection process ensures that these sites are fun and age-appropriate for our younger audience.

GOV is a general audience web site. When children under age 13 attempt to register with GOV, we ask them to have a parent or guardian establish a GOV Kid Account. The Kid Accounts feature allows GOV to obtain verifiable consent from a parent or guardian before we collect any registration information from a child we know to be under 13 years of age. In addition, Kid Accounts allow a parent to access their child's GOV Kid Account (member profile), edit personal information and better control their child's personal information. To learn more about GOV Kid Accounts, please see our Kids Account page. 

Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. GOV does not share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age. In addition, GOV will not send any direct email offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 13.  

**What else should I know about my privacy?**  

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account and personal information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.  

**Additional Information**  

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [**A2Design@aol.com**](mailto:A2Design@aol.com). 

**Also see...**

  * [**Electronic Frontier Foundation**](http://www.eff.org/) \- a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online. 
  * [**Electronic Privacy Information Center**](http://epic.org/) \- established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. 
  * [**Privacy Issues Page**](http://www.cdt.org/privacy/) \- from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT). 
  * [**The EPIC Cookies Page**](http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/) \- definitions, links, and news. 
  * [**How to Protect Your Privacy**](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission.
